

Alexandre Berthon

Product Manager



alexandreberthon.pro@gmail.com



in alexandreberthon



Paris, France

EDUCATION

MSc in Management

ESSEC Business School

MSc in Engineering

Arts et Métiers Engineering 2012 - 2015

LANGUAGES

French (Native)

English (Fluent)

Italian (Proficient)

INTERESTS

Tennis, Basketball

Sci-fi movies 👽

Video-games

CAREER PROFILE

Product Manager with a versatile skillset (engineering & business background), based in Paris, France. I thrive in challenging environments, where there is plenty of different stuff to do with different people. I can work remotely or at the office, having experienced both. Always curious about the R&D and thought processes, I thoroughly enjoy building products/features.

EXPERIENCES

Product Manager

May 2018 - Present

Coorganiz/Calizy (B2C app/SAAS provider) London, UK & Paris, FR

Working with a team scattered across Europe on 2 different projects:

- Coorganiz (B2C app, iOS/Android/web), an app that helps the organization of small communities
- · Calizy (B2B app, iOS/Android/web), a SAAS product that facilitates appointment booking for companies

Activities:

- listen to users/clients wants/needs
- · reframe those needs, so that the end feature benefits all clients and not a specific one
- · write specifications and design mockups
- project management, development follow-up
- QA (for the mobile apps: rapid remote testing via Xcode & Android Studio)
- · development and maintenance of the product landing pages: coorganiz.com, calizy.com

Platform leader

Jul 2017 - Dec 2017

Study Advisor (EdTech marketplace) Paris, FR

Overseeing the backoffice and analyzing the operational data. Objectives:

- find issues leading to basket abandonment and churn
- · find new ways to acquire users and ensure their loyalty

Software developer

Feb 2015 - Aug 2015

Lucca (HR SAAS provider) Paris, FR

Creation of a new webapp allowing the employees to improve the use of their handset with a dynamic dashboard: see their call history, make calls, match an incoming call to an entry in the company directory, etc. Considerable improvement in software engineering.

SKILLS & PROFICIENCY

HTML & CSS	
React	
R	
Python	
Sketch & Photoshop	
Premiere Pro	